Ben Zelinski

bziggz@gmail.com | Cleveland, OH | www.benzelinski.com

Profile

I'm a Software Engineer based in Cleveland, OH. I'm the co-creator of Campion, an edge-deployed, drop-in circuit breaker for distributed network architectures. I have experience with the Cloudflare (Workers, KV) and AWS (SDK, Cloudfront, IAM, Lambda@Edge, DynamoDB) ecosystems.

Skills

Backend (Node.js, Ruby, Rails, SQL, Express, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, RESTful API's)

Frontend (Javascript (ES6), JQuery, React/Redux, HTML/CSS, Pug, Bootstrap)

Cloud (AWS, Cloudflare, Heroku, Digital Ocean) | **Tools** (Github, Postman, artillery.io)

Professional Experience

Co-Creator, Software Engineer, *Campion ∂*

2020 – present

- Co-authored Campion's Case Study: https://campion-breaker.github.io/
- Co-created Campion, an edge-deployed, drop-in circuit breaker for distributed network architectures
- Designed and built on both Cloudflare and AWS platforms
- Built using Node.js, React/Redux, published to NPM
- Designed and built CLI interface for easy deployment, and GUI interface to view metrics
- Operates as a middleware proxy injected into the request/response cycle
- Speed/Load tested using artillery io over a VPN, HTTP methods tested through Postman
- Designed and built AWS architecture to deploy on Lambda@Edge
- Entire project built using remote team communication and Gitflow

Full Stack Software Engineer, *Freelance* | *Self-Employed*

2019 - present

- Developed open-source software using Node.js, Express, Ruby, Rails, Sinatra, PostgreSQL, React/Redux, vanilla JavaScript, HTML, and CSS
- Dayllo a project manager inspired by Trello built with Rails and React/Redux
- Postit a Reddit-like application built with Ruby on Rails
- Todos a todo tracker built with Node.js, Express, JavaScript, jQuery, Handlebars

Various Management Roles in Hospitality and Wine Industries

2004 - 2019

- Co-founded The Bee's Knees Baking Company NYC
- Wine Director and Manager at Mustard's Grill Napa, CA
- Sommelier Del Frisco's Chicago || Harvest Grunt Sonoma, CA

Education

Launch School, https://launchschool.com/employers 2019 - 2020Mastery-based program teaching programming with a strong emphasis on fundamentals.BFA Dramatic Performance, College-Conservatory of Music at the University of Cincinnati2000 - 2004

Awards

Eagle Scout, *BSA* 365 2000

Eagle Project of the Year for Simon Kenton Council